Previously on Prison Break:
I didn't kill that man, Michael.
If you didn't kill Terrence steadman...
...how did someone
make it look like you did?
I'm getting you out of here.
- That's impossible.
Not if you designed the place,
it isn't.
It better be open, bro.
You're asking me to break the law.
- I ask you to make a mistake.
Forget to lock up.
We're in.
Who killed Terrence steadman?
Nobody.
Terrence steadman's still alive.
Hello, Terrence.
Sound the alarm.
Hey!
No!
What do we do now?
- We run.
The escapees,
who were they?
Got a list right here.
Read it to me,
if you could.
Michael scofield,
structural engineer.
Five years for armed robbery,
Benjamin Miles Franklin.
Former U, S, Army,
Eight years for possessión of stolen goods,
John Abruzzi.
Don of the crime family of the same name,
Life without parole for
conspiracy to commit murder.
Charles "Haywire" Patoshik,
sixty years for second-degree murder.
Fernando sucre.
Five years for aggravated robbery,
David "Tweener" Apolskis.
Five years for grand larceny.
Theodore "T-Bag" Bagwell.
Life for six counts of kidnapping,
rape and first-degree murder.
And Lincoln Burrows.
Scheduled to die next week for the
murder of President Reynolds' brother,
How long has it been since
they got over the wall?
Eight o'clock last night,
scofield. He and Burrows are brothers.
- That's right.
And he's the mastermind
of this whole thing,
That's what they're saying.
I want everything they've got on him.
Where are they?
What the hell is that?
Let's go.
We gotta make it to the other side!
- What?
Make it to the other side!
- Crazy!
Come on!
- Come on, run!
We gotta go! Run!
Let's go! Move it, move it!
Go!
- The thing is gaining speed, man!
It's going too fast!
- Go through!
What?
Michael!
Hold your fire!
Freeze!
I will gun you down, scofield!
Michael, come on.
Where's the aerial unit?
- They're back on the ground refueling.
Son of a bitch.
Sir, the media is ready.
I'd like to talk about John Wilkes
Booth for a moment, if I could.
Abraham Lincoln's killer.
Twelve days.
That's how long it took to find him.
In his journal during this period,
he wrote that the shadow was his friend...
...the night his domain.
He acknowledged that
neuroses driving the criminal,,,
,,, to commit the original
crime is compounded,,,
,,, magnified by flight,
By the sounds of dogs at his heels,
Fear becomes paranoia.
Paranoia, ultimately psychosis,
I bring this up because in 140 years...
...the fundamental mind of the
escaped man has not changed.
The escaped man is still human,
he is still afraid...
...and he will stop at nothing
in his attempted flight.
Fortunately for us,,,
,,, while our quarry has
shadow and night as his ally,,,
...we have something far greater.
Televisión.
I would encourage
everyone who is watching...
...everyone in this country,
to take a good look at these faces.
These men right here are now the
eight most wanted men in America.
I thought I thought this out.
You saw all those guys back there?
The key is they're back
there and we're up here.
Yeah.
And how long is that gonna last?
Especially since we don't
have a pot to piss in...
...thanks to Abruzzi's
magically disappearing jet.
You were never gonna be on that plane.
Don't think I don't know
where you were going.
Where am I going?
- Oh, I don't know.
Utah?
You planning on telling
us about the money?
What money?
Five million dollars that Westmoreland
planted in the desert in Utah.
You don't know what you're talking about.
- You wish I didn't know.
Wait, wait.
What money?
Warden.
It's a little early for the FBI to
be showing up, don't you think?
Look, I get it.
It's still your investigation.
Once those criminals cross state lines,
it'll become a federal matter.
Yeah, well, that is not gonna happen.
- I hope you're right.
That's why I suggest that we cut through
any interagency politics from the outset.
Full transparency.
- Absolutely.
Good.
Then maybe you can tell
me about Dr. Tancredi.
There's nothing to tell.
From what I'm hearing,
she may have abetted the escapees.
Opened the door that
allowed them to get out.
Like I said, there's nothing to tell.
- You're not being very transparent, warden.
Look, I don't discuss my staff.
- Maybe you should...
...because she may be the key to this thing.
We need to speak with her.
Well, right now, Mr. Mahone,
she's not gonna be speaking with anyone.
How we doing?
Well, the IVs are hydrating her.
We've got her on naloxone infusión.
Half-milligram per hour.
What do you think the chances are?
Well, we've done everything on our end.
It's really up to her.
Either she fights and lives,
or she quits and dies.
Hey, what do you think...?
Do whatever thing you've gotta do, man.
Oh, and boy...
If you call the cops,
I will put this thing right here...
...in your eye.
Thank you.
Structural engineer, huh?
Not the kind you'd expect
to get that much ink.
Not the kind at all.
How long do you think it'd take
to get something like that done?
A hundred hours.
Two hundred.
Tattoo artist who gave it to him must've
spent a lot of time with him, then.
I'll find out who it was.
Mr. Bellick.
- Don't talk to me.
Fine. But it's gonna make
collaboration kind of hard.
Collaboration?
I got men out here in harm's way...
...and you're giving press conferences.
The press is a tool.
It'll bring those men back
quicker than bloodhounds will.
We don't need you.
We're hot on the trail,
it's a matter of time till we nail them.
The problem I find with being on a trail...
...is that, by definition,
you'll always be behind your prey.
We'll see about that.
I'm not armed.
You'll have to excuse me if I'm a
little short on trust at the moment.
I assure you, young woman,
I'm the furthest thing from a threat.
I think the Percocet pretty
much ensures that.
Good. Then you won't mind if I
capture this moment for posterity.
Won't do you any good.
You don't care that somebody's
gonna be executed for your murder?
I'm not the one who chose
Lincoln Burrows as the fall guy.
Who did?
Your sister,
the president?
You don't understand.
I'm a prisoner to all of this.
Oh, come on.
You could've come forward.
You could've stopped this thing
before it even got started.
No, I really am a prisoner.
And now you are too.
The moment you let the
door shut behind you.
Didn't it strike you as curious...
...that there wasn't any security out there?
The doors only open from the outside.
The glass is 2 inches thick, bulletproof.
There's no getting out of here,
young woman.
We gotta dump them now.
Can't.
They know about Utah.
All the more reason to dump them.
If they get caught, the feds will know
where we're going. They'll tell them.
We just gotta make sure they
stay afloat till we're off in Utah.
Doing what we gotta do.
You really think the
money's gonna be there?
Charles might've had a flexible
relationship with the truth...
...but at the end... At the end,
there'd be no reason for him to lie about it.
I figure once we bag it,
we cross over into Mexico.
Take a whole bunch of bumpy
second-class bus rides till we hit Panama.
You really got a fix on this dive shop thing?
- Yeah.
Right now, I wouldn't mind swinging in
a hammock for the next 10, 20 years.
We got half the country after us.
We ain't making it to Panama or Utah.
Not without help.
Veronica can't help us.
How can you say that?
We don't have money, clothes...
- We got all that.
I thought the plan was Abruzzi's jet.
Abruzzi's jet was plan A.
Then we got...
- Everything we need.
Where?
Storage.
Scofield designed the tattoo,
not you?
He brought the entire thing in.
Every element.
I mean, look at it.
It's the frigging sistine Chapel.
I know the guy was an engineer, but, man...
...his skill as an artist was unbelievable.
What else? What can you tell
me about him as a person?
He was cool,
you know.
But talk about a detail Nazi.
Everything had to be perfect.
Exactly as he drew it.
I always sort of had the feeling...
...that the whole thing was some sort
of inside joke that only he was in on.
We have your number, right?
Yeah.
I may be calling you.
Thank you.
Foley.
What was the name of that
road to get to the prison?
I think it was English street.
In front of the prison,
the two streets that intersect with it?
Fitz and Percy. Why?
- Thank you.
Saddle up.
- Where we going?
Somewhere we can stop being
cons and start being civilians.
Yo, why don't you cut out all the riddles,
snowflake, and just give it to us straight?
What?
Hi.
- Hi.
Well, hey,
little one.
What are you doing?
Well...
We're just fishing.
With no poles?
Well, we like to fish with our hands.
Yeah, that's it.
Hand-fishing.
I think the question is...
...what are you doing out here?
Hunting.
- Gracie?
Get away, Gracie.
Get away. Get back.
You're those guys from Fox River.
Don't any of you move a freaking muscle.
Get away from her.
Get away from her!
Okay, okay.
Just relax.
Relax.
Sir...
- You stay where you are.
No, no! John!
- Put the gun down! Put the gun down.
Let her go!
- Right now!
- John, let go of the girl.
Shut up!
- Let her go.
Put it down.
Drop the gun.
You drop the gun.
Drop it now.
You put the gun down.
One...
I'm gonna pull the trigger.
Two!
Good boy.
Get the gun.
Pick it up!
Don't you hurt her. Don't you lay a...
- Hey!
Gonna be all right.
Right?
Run to Daddy.
I ain't gonna say anything to anybody, man.
You're not gonna get hurt,
so just calm down. Where's your car?
Up on the road.
- I need your keys.
You're being considered
an accessory to this.
You know that,
don't you?
I know very little right now.
You opened the door to the infirmary
that allowed scofield to escape.
Didn't you?
- No.
You have a sexual relationship with him?
But you had feelings for him.
Seven other men got out,
you know.
Who?
I'm sorry, sir, it's saturday.
We're not open.
Well, that's sort of the point.
Sorry, sir?
See, I'm gonna need some work done
and I'm gonna need it done privately.
I'm sorry,
you said you needed the work done?
This is a medical clinic,
isn't it?
Well, of course it is, sir,
but for animals.
God, man,
what happened to you?
You need medical attention.
No.
- I'm gonna get an ambulance.
Nobody's gonna be doing
any calling here, doctor.
Fine.
That's right.
What do you want?
You know what?
That's it.
I want Eyetie out of the car right now, man.
That was a little girl.
Don't you have a heart?
God, I have a daughter.
I have a little girl.
I got one too.
But if I hadn't done what I had to do...
...we wouldn't be on our
way to see them right now.
Turn right up there.
Whoa, hold on.
Where we going?
Oswego.
That's west, man. We need to go east.
My family's back in Chicago.
And you think the cops don't know about it?
You think they're not just sitting there...
...waiting for you to come
running back home?
What's the matter with you?
What about New York?
- What about it?
My girl's pregnant, bro.
Understand, your love is
your weakness right now.
And they know about it.
- Doesn't mean it has to stop you.
You just gotta be smart about it.
And get to oswego.
Oswego is not on the way, snowflake.
It's not where oswego is.
It's what's in oswego.
Captain, scofield's credit-card
transaction history.
Spent money in Will County
before he was incarcerated.
Exactly.
- He's from Chicago.
Why does a guy from Chicago come here...
...and spend 8 grand in all
these places in a month?
Car wash, voice mail, storage,
car rental.
We got guys looking into it.
- Good.
What about the feds? Should we tell?
- What do you think?
Captain Bellick,
we got something.
Hunter up by Tamarack just
ran into five of the cons.
So this is where scofield lived.
Yeah, up until about two months
ago when he was incarcerated.
Mother's dead,
father's a deadbeat.
Got nothing in the whole
worid but your brother.
So you plan.
And you scheme for months...
...until you get it right.
Every single element.
And then you destroy all the evidence.
I want divers down in the river.
You won't get cell coverage.
We're in the middle of nowhere.
Those digital carriers don't have cell
towers way out here in Western Montana.
How about shutting up, Terrence?
- Just trying to save you some effort.
They're like a web, these people.
Harder you struggle, worse it gets.
Sounds to me like a coward
trying to justify himself.
If I stay out of the way and stay quiet,
I stay alive.
That's what they said.
That's what they told me.
And you want to live like this?
In a hermetically sealed box...
...while everything out there goes to hell?
- Self-preservation is a strong motivator.
So's the truth.
Don't.
Young woman.
Do not.
Don't.
How you doing, buddy?
I'm pretty freaked out,
that's how I'm doing.
They took your car,
didn't they?
1978 Grand Cherokee?
Yeah.
- Which way did they go?
Up that way.
North, toward oswego.
Oswego.
Pardon me.
Scofield's paperwork,
get it to me.
That credit card stuff.
Right here, captain.
Of course.
Where else you gonna put all
the crap you need to disappear?
We're going to oswego, boys.
You have a visitor.
Thank you.
Thanks.
You look disappointed.
No, I thought you were gonna be my father.
You heard from him?
His office.
Well, brought you a change of clothes.
Figured, you know.
- Thanks.
And your purse.
You left it in the infirmary.
I'm in a lot of trouble,
I think.
I...
I need to apologize to you.
They threatened my job if I didn't talk, and...
No, no.
No.
One thing you learn when
you're walking the steps...
...is that you never outsource the blame
that belongs in your own back yard.
Well...
...you're not the first correctional
worker that fell for a con.
Trust me.
He never cared.
Not one bit.
What are you thinking about?
Mistakes.
You had to do it.
Not like I did.
I ruined her life.
There's nothing you can do about it now.
- That's not true.
You fell for her, huh?
Where's oswego?
Half a mile, maybe.
Good.
What are you gonna do, Terrence,
shoot me?
Blow my guts all over the house?
Then what?
You can't leave, remember?
You kill me,
you're stuck with me.
I'm safe here.
You're a prisoner here.
But I'm still breathing.
If I go outside...
...one step,
I won't be.
You look at me like I'm the devil.
I gave up my family.
My teeth.
I eat Percocet all day...
...just to dull the pain of
my miserable existence.
You have no idea what I've been through.
- What you've been through?
This isn't about you, Terrence.
Don't.
Blackfoot Sheriff's Department,
Hello?
Hello, my name's Veronica Donovan.
I need you to send a unit to the house at
the end of Light Road as soon as possible.
I'm sorry, ma'am,
are you calling to report a crime?
Yeah.
By the president of the United states.
Send the car.
I'm sorry, sir,
I don't think I can do this.
There are nerves.
Look...
You need a specialist.
- I don't...
You need somebody who
knows what they're doing.
I don't have the luxury of choice here.
My hand has been in that
box for hours now. It is dying.
Sir, I am not capable of doing this.
I only have one hand, but I can stick this
in your neck before you get to that door.
Now, if that's not incentive enough for you,
I see that you have a Mrs. Gudat out there.
With a name like that in a county like this...
...old Mrs. Gudat would not be
too hard to find, now, would she?
Fine.
I can promise you nothing.
Story of my life.
I'll have to put you under.
Do I really look that stupid?
Sir, I cannot do a procedure
like this without an anesthetic.
I have to cut away dead flesh.
Nobody can undergo a procedure
like this without an anesthetic.
I ain't nobody.
Schweitzer was the company
that made the toilet scofield
took off to get out of his cell.
The Allen bolt was the fitting.
- It's all here, isn't it?
Yeah.
- It's amazing.
Ripe Chance Woods. Is there a
place in the vicinity with that name?
Got someone looking into it.
DoC's moving on a
storage facility in oswego.
Captain, manager says that scofield's
got a lease on Unit 164. still active.
We have guys on 8th street,
3rd street and in the alley.
Lf they're in there, we got them boxed.
- We push right up the gut, then.
Any one of them makes a threatening
move, put a hole in them.
You got it.
Officer.
This is my collar, smart guy.
Back the hell off.
Close the door.
Still nothing on this place?
Nope.
They're coming back with nothing.
No place by that name
anywhere in this country...
...or any other country for that matter.
Let's go.
Son of a bitch set us up.
Not one word.
Officer.
Nothing.
Oh, that kid's clever.
It's not a place,
it's a name.
Your PDA, you got it?
- Yeah.
Bring up the census of this county.
Far back as it goes.
Well, somebody's gonna see us.
- Keep digging.
We're gonna go to hell, guys.
Swear to God, we're gonna go to hell.
Help me out.
You are one sick cat,
you know that?
What are you looking for?
We gotta go to the cemetery.
Now.
Originally, this was supposed to be a
week's worth of clothes for me and Linc.
But I figured you all need just
as much help as we do, so...
You're doing this out of the
goodness of your heart?
Right, John, the heart.
You remember what that is, don't you?
Damn, snowflake,
this is tight, man.
It's like I said,
we gotta stop being cons...
...start being civilians.
Nice. The trousers are a little bit too short,
don't you think?
Chop your feet off.
You're good at that.
This jacket isn't exactly the best thing.
You know what I'm saying?
- You want variety, hit Target.
Linc.
What have we got?
Money, passports...
...prepaid phone cards.
Archie Ryan?
- You see mine?
Phineas McClintock.
Whoa, and these?
Keys to a car that's waiting for us a
couple of hundred yards from here.
That a two-of-us or five-of-us?
That's a two-of-us.
They know?
- Not yet.
Guys, guys.
We got company.
We gotta roll.
How did he know?
We're civilians.
Remember that.
I'm sorry. Do you know what time it is?
- No, I'm sorry.
I can't go outside.
They'll kill me as soon as I show my face.
You're wrong about that.
As soon as you show your face,
this whole thing is gonna be over.
You can have your life back, Terrence.
Promise?
- I promise.
Hello?
V, it's me.
Linc?
- We're out,
oh, thank God you're okay.
I saw the news. You gotta stop.
I need you to turn yourself in,
- What?
I found steadman.
I'm with him now, Linc. He's alive.
You're gonna be exonerated.
Come in.
- Steadman?
What are you talking,
you found steadman?
Terrence, come on, let's go.
- Afternoon.
Veronica,
- The police are here.
Look, I need you to stay where you are.
Ma'am,
- I don't wanna lose you.
Ma'am, put the phone down.
- What?
Mr. Steadman,
take a few steps back.
Ver... Veronica?
Veronica?
Oh, my God.
Veronica!
I thought you knew that all calls to the
local station are routed through us.
This is federal land, remember?
And as for your little toy here.
It's contraband.
You gonna tell us how you got it in there?
- I brought it when I got here.
Whatever for?
- To protect myself.
That's what we're here for, remember?
In less than a day,
the trail has gone cold,,,
,,, in pursuit of what are being
called the Fox River Eight...
That's fine.
Stay on top of it, all right?
DoC's still doing a sweep of oswego
but they have basically vanished.
I wouldn't be sure about that, Ives.
- Don't know how you can be so confident.
It's not like they left a
map where they're going.
Actually, that's exactly what they did.
Scofield had the entire thing on his body.
How to get out of that prison,
how to disappear afterward,
It's all there,
I promise you that it's only a matter
of time before we know everything...
...that is in scofield's head.
Where he plans to run to,
how he plans to get there,
So when the time comes
that he does get there,,,
...we'll be waiting for him.